Brave Exkaiser
勇 者 エクスカイザ- 용자 엑스카이저
Over a million of them shine with a blue light
靑く輝く 幾千万の 푸르게 빛나는 몇천만개의
The shards of love have scattered
愛のかけらが ちりばめられた 사랑의 조각들이 흩어져 있어
It's brewing in this world
この 地球(ほし)の中 蠢く 이 지구 안에 휘몰아치는
A storm that you'll confront
嵐に向かう 폭풍우로 달려가는
And because I believe in you
君を信じたから 너를 믿으니까
I'm not afraid of anything
何も恐れないさ 아무것도 두렵지 않아
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
Courage and friendship
勇氣と友情！ 용기와 우정!
That moment when we join our strength GATHER WAY
力 あわせた その 時 GATHER AWAY 힘을 합치는 그순간 GATHER AWAY
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
I'd almost forgotten it
忘れかけていた！ 잊고 있었던
The fiery burning and important PASSIONATE feeling in my heart
熱く 燃える 大切な PASSIONATE この 胸に 뜨겁게 불타는 소중한 PASSIONATE내 가슴에!
This mysterious and boundless Universe...
신비하고 광대한 우주 성우:山寺宏一야마데라 코이치
It was here that the evil energy life forms, the space pirate Geisters,
그 안에 악의 에너지 생명체 우주 해적 가이스터가
set their sights on the treasures of humans and snuck onto Earth.
인류의 보물을 노리고 지구로 잠입했다
Their first target was the newly completed Linear Motor Car.
처음으로 그들이 노린 것은
After learning about this, Exkaiser of the cosmic police called Blue Raker and Green Raker to aid in the rescue.
그걸 알아챈 우주 경찰 엑스카이저는
By transforming into King Exkaiser, they spoiled the Geisters' plans.
자신도 킹 엑스카이저로 변신해 카이스터의 음모를 꺾었다
This is the story of the battle between good and evil that has spanned across the universe,
이것은 우주에 퍼지고 있는 악과 싸우는
and of brave Exkaiser and his comrades.
용자 엑스카이저와 그 동료들의 이야기이다
Giant Power Failure, Total Chaos
第３話　大停電で大こんらん 第３話　대정전으로 대혼란! 1990/2/17
Asahidai Primary School
朝日台小學敎 아사히다이 소학교
3rd Year Class B
3학년 B반
Here are the different types of power plants that create electricity.
이렇게 전기는 발전소에서 만들어져서
The power travels via power lines to transformer substations, which leads to all your houses.
송전선을 통해 변전소로 보내지고 그 다음에 여러분들 집에 공급되는 거예요
Kotomi-chan, could you list the different means to generate power?
코토미! 발전소의 종류에는 뭐뭐가 있죠?
Yes! Hydro power, steam power, and nuclear power.
네! 수력, 화력, 원자력 발전소가 있습니다
That is correct.
맞아요
But those aren't the onnly ones.
그리고 전기는 발전소뿐만 아니라
We also have solar power--
태양을 이용한 솔라시스템(Solar System)등이..
Huh? What's wrong? Is the electricity off? What should I do?
무슨 일이지? 전기가 안켜지네.. 어떻게 된거지?
I'm scared!
싫어, 무서워..
Don't worry. It's just a power failure.
걱정하지마, 잠깐 정전 된거야
Kotomi-chan, leave this to me!
코토미, 나한테 맡겨
Such situations call for the Super Light!
이런 때를 대비해서 파워강 슈퍼라이트를 준비했지
Huh? It's not working. Come on--
어, 안되네...이게..이게...
Why so alarmed, Takumi-kun?
뭘 그렇게 복잡하게 해, 타쿠미
What could have gone wrong...?
그게...저...어떻게 된거지...
Eh!? What did you say!? Chief! We got trouble!
에~뭐라구? 편집장님 큰일났습니다!
Keep quiet... what's all the fuss about?
거참 시끄럽게..왠 호들갑인가?
Every city is reporting a massive power failure!
각지에서 정전소동이 벌어졌습니다
-A massive power failure? -Yes, it looks like someone is stealing the electricity.
정전 소동? /누군가 전기를 빼내가는 것 같습니다
What!?
뭐라고?
Oh! We're also havinng a power failure!
오~! 이젠 우리 회사도 정전됐네요!
What's so funny!? I just finished writing that copy!
이게 웃을 일인가! 남은 힘들여 쓴 원고를 날렸는데!
Donn't worry, chief!
편집장님도 걱정도 팔자십니다!
Our company has its own generator, so we can deal with any power failure.
우리 회사는 자가 발전 장치가 있어서 정전이 되도 금방 정상화 된다니까요
But everything I wrote is gone!
쓴 기사는 날아가고 없잖나!
Ohh, so when you're using a word processor, when the power goes out,
오~ 워드프로세서는 한번 전기가 나가면 쓴 글이 지우개로 지우듯 사라지는 거군요~
This is no time to be impressed!
입 떡벌리고 감탄할 일인가!
Hmm? I wonder why they've stopped at such a place...
음? 어째서 저 열차는 저런 곳에 서 있는 거지?
What!? A power failure has stopped all lines!?
뭐? 정전으로 모든 선로가 불통이라고?
But we're running smoothly over here.
하지만 우리 열차는 달리고 있는데?
Oops!
들키겠다!
What's wrong? Hey! Are you all right? Hello?
무슨 일이야? 괜찮아? 이봐! 여보세요!
Oh, we stopped! I guess there is a power failure.
아..아...멈췄다 역시 우리 열차도 정전이다
What? A power failure stopped all the trains?
뭐라고? 정전으로 모든 열차가 멈췄다는 건가?
Yup. Since I'm not running on electricity, I almost gave myself away.
그렇다, 나는 전기로 움직이는 게 아니어서 까딱하면 정체를 들킬 판이었다 危うく正體を知られるところだったよ
It couldn't be the Geisters' doing, could it?
혹시 카이스터의 소행이 아닐까 싶다
Possibly.
가능성 있는 말이다
Anyway, thanks for the report.
아무튼 계속 보고하라
Crap!
들키겠군!
Oh, it's you, Kouta.
코우타..
We got a trouble, Exkaiser!
엑스카이저, 큰일났어
There's a massive power failure all over Japan!
일본 여기저기서 정전소동이야
All over Japan?
일본 여기저기서?
The news said someone might be stealing the electricity which is why we're having blackouts.
전기를 보내는 송전선에서 전기를 누군가가 훔쳐간다는 뉴스를 들었어
It's being stolen?
전기를 훔쳐간다고?
Maybe it's the Geisters again...
또 가이스터 짓일까?
Without power, I can't watch TV, and it'll be too dark at night to go to restrooms!
전기가 안들어 오면 TV도 못보고 밤엔 너무 캄캄해서 화장실도 못가
And that would also stop the Shinkansen?
그래서 신칸선도 멈춘거군
They stopped?
신칸선이 멈췄어?
I had a report from Blue Raker just now.
블루 레이커에게서 방금 보고받았다
Drill Max, do you copy?
드릴 맥스 들리나?
This is Drill Max!
여기는 드릴 맥스! ドリルマックス
What's up? Do I got work to do?
잘 들립니다, 무슨 일이 있는 겁니까?
Electricity is being stolen in all the places.
도처에서 전기를 도난당하고 있다
Please investigate the power plants and cables.
곧 바로 송전선을 조사해 주길 바란다
Roger! I'll report back shortly.
알았습니다, 즉시 조사하겠습니다
So that was Drill Max...
방금 전에 드릴 맥스라고 하는 것 같았는데
Besides Blue Raker and Green Raker, do you have any other friends around?
블루레이커랑 그린레이커 외에도 동료가 있는 거야?
Yup. There's also Dash Max and Sky Max.
그외에도 드릴맥스와 스카이맥스가 있다
They are all Kaisers of the cosmic police.
모두를 일컬어 우주경찰 카이저스라고 한다
There are that many!?
그렇게 많이 있었네
This...
이건...!
It must be an electric condenser!
전기를 모아두는 축전기(蓄電機)잖아?
The Geisters' mark..
가이스터 문장..
I guess it was their doing!
역시 녀석들의 소행이었군
That should do it.
이젠 됐다
Time to replace the battery...
자, 곧 전지교환 시간이군 암모사우루스(Ammosaurus)형 로봇
What!? You are--!
오! 넌!
You're Armor Geist!
네 녀석은 암모 가이스터!
I will not allow your type to disturb the peace of the Earth!
이 평화로운 지구를 혼란에 빠뜨리는 자는 この平和な地球を混亂に陷れようとするヤツは
Give up!
각오해라!
Crap!
당하겠다!
He ran... Slippery bastard...
도망갔군! 잽싼 녀석!
Guess it really was the Geisters' handiwork.
역시 가이스터가 저지른 짓이었어
Seems so. But the power should be back now.
그래, 하지만 지금쯤 정전소동은 진정됐을 거다
Since we destroyed their equipment.
녀석들이 설치한 장치를 파괴시켰기 때문이다
It's true! What a relief!
정말이네, 다행이야
However, it's still too early to rejoice....
하지만 기뻐할 수만은 없다
How come?
왜?
Electricity is an important treasure to human life..
전기는 인간생활에 있어서 소중한 보물이다
Knowing this, the Geisters' boss won't stop until he gets it.
그러니 가이스터의 두목이 이 정도로 물러나리라고는 볼 수 없다
Then, there's gonna be another power failure?
그러면, 다시 정전될지도 모른다는 거네?
All right, tell those dirtbags this....
알겠나?
It's futile to just steal electricity from remote areas.
전기를 조금 훔치는 것으로는 일이 안된다
If you want to get it done, target the source!
그러니 전기의 근원지를 노려라! 電氣を作っている元を狙え
I have orders from Dino Geist-sama!
다이노 가이스터님으로부터의 지령이다
Target the source of the electricity!
전기를 만드는 근원지를 노리라고 하셨다
And just where is that?
만드는 근원지가 어딘데?
The nuclear power plant.
원자력 발전소다!
Nuclear power plannt?
원자력 발전소?
Well now, why is the electricity being stolen?
자 그럼, 어째서 전기를 도난당한 건지
I'm sure I'll find something out if I investigate this nuclear power plant!
이 걸 알아보기 위해서는 원자력 발전소를 취재하면 뭔가가 나올 거라 이거지
I sure am a genius!
나 정말 머리 좋단말야~
Here we go!
그러면!
Ah... I forgot my camera...
카..카메라 두고 왔다!
Chief is gonna be angry at me again...
또 편집장님한테 깨지겠군
That's the nuclear power plant.
저기 원자력 발전소다
You lost what you were writing, papa?
아빠도 원고 날리셨어요?
Yeah.
그래
We had so many problems at school because we couldn't use the computers!
우리 학교도 컴퓨터를 못써서 난리도 아니예요
But thanks to that, our computer class become self-study time.
덕분에 컴퓨터 수업시간에 자습했어요
I bet you were just playing around.
자습이라고 하지만 사실 노는 시간 아냐?
Excuse me?
뭘 모르면 가만 있어!
Do you know how hard it is to calculate without the computer!?
컴퓨터가 해야할 계산을 내가 하느라고 얼마나 머리 터졌는데!
But isn't that a good thing?
잘 된 일이네
Why's that?
어째서요?
Since you got to study arithmetic.
산수공부가 된거잖아?
That's right. If you rely too much on computers, you'll forgot how to do simple additions and subtractions.
그래, 컴퓨터에만 의존하면 덧셈 뺄셈을 잘 못하게 된단다 足たし算:덧셈 引き算:뺄셈
It was worse for me!
엄마는 더 큰 일이야
I couldn't do the laundry or cleaning!
세탁기하고 청소기가 돌아가질 않으니 내가 다 해야 하거든
But isn't that good?
잘 됐잖아요!
Since you got to the laundry and cleaning yourself.
손수 세탁이랑 청소 할 수 있으니까!
That's right. If you rely too much on laundry machines and cleaners, you'll just nap and eat all day.
그래, 세탁기 청소기에만 의지하면 삼시 세끼 밥먹고 잠밖에 더 자겠냐?
Come on!
이 사람이!
Oh! That's not what I meant!
아..아니, 그런 의미가 아니라..
Anyway, we seem to be too dependent on machines these days!
어쨌든 요즘엔 기계에 너무 의지해서 너무 편해졌다는 거야
Maybe a power failure is a good thing every now and then!
가끔 정전도 괜찮을 지 모르겠네
Again?
또야?
Ow! Who put a chair in such a place!?
아야! 누구야! 여기에 저거 둔 사람이!
Papa?
여보~ 어머!
What's wrong?
어떻게 된 거예요?
But now we can't watch TV!
하지만 이젠 TV도 못보게 생겼네요
And I can't read my paper...
신문 읽기도 글렀구만
And you just said an occasional power failure is good...
가끔 정전도 괜찮다고 했으면서..
Well, now we can be together and talk like a family!
그래, 이렇게 가족들이 얼굴 맞대고 こうやって家族が顔を近づけて
A wonderful resolution!
가족화목이라... 一家團欒
Hoshikawa residence!
네, 호시카와입니다
Oh, Tokuda-san! Whatt's wrong?
토쿠다씨 왜 그렇게 허둥대세요?
Let me take that.
그래, 바꿨네
What? The nuclear power plant is under attack!?
뭐? 원자력 발전소가 공격당하고 있다고?
The power line towers started moving and are heading this way!
주위에 세워진 철탑이 움직이더니 이곳으로 오고 있습니다
All right, you continue gathering information..
알았네, 자넨 취재를 계속하게
Something terrible has happened...
난처한 일이 벌어졌군
Should something happen to that nuclear power plant, the entire Kanto region would be affected!
만약 원자력 발전소가 공격당하면 방사선으로 관동일대에 사람이 살 수 없게 돼
What!?
네?
Papa, where are you going?
아빠, 어디 가세요?
To the reading room! I'm going to write an article with the computer.
서재!  컴퓨터로 기사를 보내야 겠다
But there's a power failure!
하지만 정전이잖아요!
That computer is connected to the power generator at work, so it should be fine.
저 컴퓨터는 회사에 자가발전으로 연결되어 있어서 괜찮아
I have to tell Exkaiser!
엑스카이저에게 알려줘야 해
What? They're after the nuclear power plant?
뭐? 원자력 발전소가 공격당한다고?
That's right! Do something!
그래, 어떻게 좀 해봐!
Right.
알았다
All of us Kaisers will stop them!
카이저스 전원을 불러 막아내겠다
I'm going too!
나도 갈래
No, I cannot take you to such a dangerous place.
아니, 그건 안된다
But--!
하지만...!
Let me give you this.
너에게 이걸 주겠다
What's this?
이건 뭐야?
Kaiser Brace. It's a walkie-talkie.
카이저 브레스, 무전기다 カイザ-ブレス Kaiser bracelet
With that, you can keep in contact with me.
그걸로 언제든 나와 교신 할 수 있다
Well, I will be going!
그러면, 난 출발한다!
Exkaiser! Good luck!
브레스...엑스카이저 잘 해야해!
If you have any more information, let me know.
또 다른 정보가 생기면 연락해 다오!
Right!
알았어
To all the Kaisers!
카이저스 전원에게 알린다
Move out to the nuclear power plant immediately!
지구 원자력 발전소로 급히 달려가라!
The water level is dropping!
수위가 내려가고 있습니다
Core projecting level 8!
핵융합 발생 방사능 레벨 8
What is it?
어떻게 된 겁니까?
The cooling towers have been destroyed and a meltdown just begun!
냉각파이프가 파괴되서 핵융합이 시작됐습니다
What!?
뭐라고요?
Ready and waiting.
준비 완료됐다!
All right, let's go!
좋아, 시작하자!
What is it!?
무슨 일이지?
Now what?
뭐지?
We did it!
해냈구만
Of course! Since it was my plan...
당연하지, 이 몸께서 짠 작전이거든
Huh? Kaisers!
어? 카이저스!
Change, Dash Max!
Change ! Dash Max! チェ-ンジ !  ダッシュマックス! 체인지! 대쉬 맥스!
Change, Drill Max!
Change! Drill Max! チェ-ンジ ! ドリルマックス! 체인지! 드릴 맥스!
Change, Sky Max!
Change! Sky Max! チェ-ンジ ! スカイマックス! 체인지! 스카이 맥스!
Max Team, arrives!
マックスチ-ム 見參 맥스팀! 견참(등장)!
More robots!
또 로봇이 나타났다!
You fiendish Geisters!
가이스터 악당들아!
We will not allow you to proceed!
너희들의 만행을 용서할 수 없다
Shut up! Get 'em!
시끄러! 해치워라!
All right!
해냈다!
Max Team, Form Up!
Maxteam Form Up! マックスチ-ム  フォ-ム アップ ! 맥스팀 폼 업!
Triple Fusion, God Max!
Three-body union God Max! 三體合體 ゴッドマックス! 삼체합체 갓맥스 !
Flying God Bomb!
Flying God bomb フライングゴッドボム! 플라인 갓 밤!
Shit!
이런!
You guys, combine!
너희들도 합체해!
Damn, It's huge!
무지 크구만...
All right, now's our chance!
됐다, 바로 지금이다!
멈춰라!
멈춰라!
엑스카이저!
엑스카이저!
Change, Blue Raker!
Change! Blue Raker!
Change, Green Raker!
Change! Green Raker!
Raker Brothers!
Raker Brothers!
Exkaiser, you bastard--!
엑스카이저, 너 이놈!
Return the nuclear power plant!
발전소를 제자리로 돌려놔라!
Forget it! You gotta be joking!
천만의 말씀! 웃기고 있구만!
King Loader!
King Loader キング-ロ-ダ- 킹 로더!
Giant Fusion, King Exkaiser!
Huge union King Exkaiser 巨大合體 キングエクスカイザ 거대합체 킹엑스카이저!
Form Up!
Form Up! フォ-ムオブ! 폼 업!
Left Right Fusion, Ultra Raker!
좌우합체 울트라 레이커! 左右合體ウルトラレイカ-
Kaiser Blaster!
Kaiser Blaster カイザ-ブラスタ- 카이저 블러스터!
Ultra Double Chain Crusher!
Ultra double chain crusher ウルトラダブルチェ-ンクラッシャ- 울트라 더블 체인 크러셔!
We should retreat!
이쯤에서 일단은 후퇴하자
God Sonic Buster!
God Sonic Buster ゴッドソニックバスタ- 갓 소닉 버스터!
Oh no! We have only three minutes before the power plant explodes!
큰 일이다! 이대로는 앞으로 3분 내에 원자력 발전소가 폭발해 사라지게 된다
What!?
네?
Exkaiser! This is bad! The power plant is gonna explode in 3 minutes!
엑스카이저, 큰 일이야 앞으로 3분내에 발전소가 폭발한대!
Everyone, scramble!
모두 서둘러!
Right!
음!
God Slicer!
God slicer ゴッドスライサ- 갓 슬라이서
All right! Now!
좋아, 지금이다!
Good, let's go!
됐다, 출발한다!
Leave the rest to me!
뒷 일은 내가 맡겠다!
Kaiser Sword!
Kaiser Sword カイザ-ソド 카이저 소드!
Thunder Flash!
Thunder Flash! サンダ-フラッシュ! 썬더 플래쉬!
Yay! They did it!
야호~! 해치웠다!
It's no use! I can't stop it from exploding! It'll blow in 30 seconds!
틀렸어, 멈출 수가 없다 앞으로 30초면 폭발한다!
What!?
뭐요?
We must bring the nuclear energy under control!
원자로의 에너지를 진정시켜야 한다
Right!
알았다!
Anti-energy Beam, fire!
반에너지 광선 방사! 反エネルギ-光線
This can't be!
이건 말도 안돼!
Tokuda Osamu, dead at 28 years old...
토쿠다 오사무가 28세의 나이로 운명을 달리하는 건가!!
Father! Mother! Forgive your idiot son!
어머니, 아버지 불효자를 용서하세요!
The nuclear power is subsiding!
어? 원자로가 식고있다!
It stopped!
머...멈췄다!
I'm saved!
아~~살았다!
We did it!
해냈다!
What a relief!
이걸로 한걱정 덜었다
Kouta, you can relax now.
코우타, 이제 걱정할 것 없다
The power plant is safe.
발전소는 안전하다
Thank you, Exkaiser!
고마워, 엑스카이저!
Papa! They said that the nuclear power plant won't explode now!
아빠, 발전소가 지금은 폭발위험성이 사라졌대요
Thank god!
거참 다행이구나
Huh? How do you know that?
그런데, 어떻게 그걸 알았냐?
They said that it might take 3 days to completely fix the power grid.
정전이 완전히 정상화 되려면 3일정도 걸린다나봐
Until then, it'll be pitch black at night and I won't be able to watch TV...
그때까지는 밤에는 캄캄할테고 TV도 볼 수 없어
I see.
그렇군
But mama said that because of it, we can all get closer like a family.
하지만 엄마는 정전 덕에 가족이 화목해지고
And she's happy that she can relax during the afternoon.
게다가 야근안해도 된다고 좋아하시지만..
Then that's a good thing.
그렇다면 다행이다
I guess so.
그렇긴 해
Well, I better get going!
그럼, 나 학교 갔다 올게
Sure.
그래
Mario.
마리오!
You don't need electricity, right?
너한테는 전기가 필요 없지?
Faraway wind carries your dream
遙かな 風が 夢を 運んで 아득한 바람이 꿈을 가져와
What could you discover from this excited feeling
ときめく 事に 何を 見つけるの 설레이는 일에서 무엇을 찾아낼까
Dreams get bigger strongly and fast
强く 早く ふくらむ 夢に 강하고 빠르게 부풀어 오르는 꿈에
Don't forget to be who you are
自分らしさ 忘れずに 자신다운 모습을 잊지 말고
Embrace your enthusiastic heart
夢中に なれる 心 抱きしめ 정열적인 마음 꼭 껴안고
And try walking that path
その 道を 步いてみてね 그 길을 걸어가 보는거야
You know what?
ボクね
When I grow up, I wanna be the pilot of a space shuttle
大きくなったら
But right before our eyes, the Geisters are trying to steal the launching rocket
なのにガイスタ-のやつらが,ボクたちの目の前で
Exkaiser! Hurry!
エクスカイザ-,早く來て！
If you don't stop them, we'll never reach Mars!
あれが飛ばないと,火星に基地が作れないんだよ！
Next on Brave Exkaiser,
次回、勇者エクスカイザ- 『火星行きロケットしゅっぱ-つ！』
Is there an alien in your home, too?
君んちにも宇宙人、いる？ 第４話　火星行きロケットしゅっぱ?つ！ 1990/2/24